# Nick Little

10 Hamlett Drive
Two Roads
Woodend
New Zealand
+64 21 047 2244
nick@nlittle.com
linkedin.nlittle.com

## **Profile**

Strategically minded candidate containing a breadth of experience across a variety of information technology disciplines, with in-depth working knowledge of cloud services and proven success implementing cloud solutions. An ITIL certified leader currently consulting with both public and private entities wanting to migrate away from on premise systems and services.

## Professional Experience

Ministry for Primary Industries **Solutions Architect**2019 - Present

- Consulting with the CTO, internal and external clients to implement a business best practice around how to securely provide remote access from mobile phones to internal legacy applications. This was achieved through solution design and options analysis resulting in the use of Azure Active Directory Application proxy to deliver secure remote access to internal legacy MPI applications. This is now one of our architectural design patterns/building blocks we can provide as a solution to other projects across MPI.
- Consulting with clients to address the problem of migrating our HRIS (HR) and FMIS (finance) systems which have integrations located both in the cloud and on-premise. This required solution design and resulted in leveraging Apigee API gateway cloud to publish and expose RESTful web services (API's) to enable legacy on-premise flat file integrations to communicate with the new cloud based HRIS and FMIS solutions. It also involved a Cloud migration from the NZ government private cloud HRIS and finance solutions to AWS.
- Member of the Strategy & Assurance team, provide Solution and Enterprise Architecture services and assurance to project and BAU teams across MPI's over 5,000 staff, and 10 business units. Create architectural artifacts including solution option design papers, solution architecture designs, as built documents, technical and high level solution design diagrams using Archimate, SparxEA, UML and TOGAF. Involvement with projects from inception to delivery, by providing a helicopter view. Work

with vendors and technical leads to provide governance, Certification & Assurance sign-off resulting in successful project delivery. This includes providing budgeting and risk benefit/cost analysis to provide risk assurance to the SLT.

- Influence others, and manage expectations/relationships including with senior leaders to achieve the desired best fit outcomes and strategically aligned best practise industry standard solutions.
- Work alongside other architects to define the Solution and Enterprise Architecture Strategies.

## Timely Limited

## Infrastructure Engineer

2018 - 2019

- Working with senior developers and the CTO to develop a strategy and architecture solution design
  for deploying and rolling back production code, after user error issues with manual deployments
  which had severely impacted our clients. Using Azure DevOps CI/CD pipelines and Infrastructure as
  Code (IaC) to deploy consistent code and infrastructure resources across all environments.
- Defining and implementing a client strategy to migrate our apps from deprecated Azure Cloud Services to Azure Web Apps before services were impacted. This required changing all DNS and networks to Cloudflare, using real time load balancing and traffic scaling for zero downtime access using the Cloudflare API/Javascript workers, and custom API's.
- Working with clients to migrate to Azure KeyVault to ensure plain text passwords aren't stored in cloud GIT repositories and can't be compromised.
- After auditing our internal systems and processes, some gaps needed filled. Solution Architecture
  and implementation in Azure including Tenancy Design to isolate environment subscriptions and
  setup role based access control to resources
- Consulted with clients after diagnosing that some of their customers were not receiving email notifications from the Timely app. ISP was blocking emails as spam. Re-designed our email sending system using SendGrid to add SPF/DKIM DNS records to ensure emails are delivered reliably.
- Working with CFO/CTO to reduce financial overheads in multiple subscriptions across cloud services by decommissioning a 3rd party cloud backup service, and utilising AWS cloud backup.
- Solution and Infrastructure Architecture including monitoring/incident resolution across Amazon Web Services and Azure using Docker, Node.JS, Terraform, Ansible, Azure Resource Manager deployment templates, GIT, NewRelic, RayGun, PagerDuty, and Kubernetes.

## Middleware New Zealand Limited

# **Middleware Technical Specialist**

2016 - 2017

- Working as a contract consultant in multi-vendor environments across multiple private and public organisations to define API, authentication/authorisation and Identity and Access Management strategies
- Facilitating client workshops and whiteboard sessions to show clients how they could adopt
  Axway/Apigee API gateway. Demonstrating the value it would add by enabling better security,
  scalability, auditing/logging, ease of developers publishing new API's, inbuilt authentication and
  authorisation.
- Consulting with clients on Google Cloud Platform (GCP)/Amazon Web Services (AWS) and presenting proof of concepts to illustrate the value of improved security, monitoring, logging, access, and speed by migrating away from local data centres. This involved setting up new

- environments in Google Cloud/AWS, and migrating clients test data to show a real world use-case of their setup.
- Contract consultant to work with clients and other agencies to contribute to delivering the NZ
  government's 104 million dollar Joint Border Management System (JBMS). Utilising Axway API
  gateway on the NZ government private cloud, and creating the Solutions Architectural resources
  including the As-Built and Solution Architecture Design Documents.
- BAU monitoring and responding to events for API gateway environments to meet SLA"s across
  multiple private and public companies using Linux, Windows, Axway and Apigee API Gateway,
  Mulesoft, IBM DB2, WebSphere, CRON jobs, Nasgios, Thruk, SNMP, SMS alerts, and Splunk.

#### **NEC New Zealand**

# **Systems Engineer Global Safety Division**

2015 - 2016

- Consultant contractor based on client site (New Zealand Police). Consulting and delivering on projects: AFIS to ABIS (Automated Fingerprint/Biometric Identification Systems) migration, including digital transformation of manual paper ink fingerprints to digital, and LiveScan fingerprint kiosks deployed NZ wide.
- Receive and facilitate training for NZ Police staff on new project delivery.
- Working in a multi-vendor global domain, across many time-zones. 24/7 high availability systems, tier 3 support and maintenance.
- BAU management of the NZ Police biometrics systems running on bespoke virtualized NEC RedHat
  Enterprise Linux Solution comprising of .NET, Java, JBoss middleware, C++, and Oracle databases.
  With HP 3Par SAN storage, Dell physical blade servers, and Cisco network switches. Including
  regular offsite tape backups in multiple data centres. Installation/issue resolution of new servers,
  networks, and equipment in NZ police co-located data centres.

# **ADInstruments**

## **Technical Support Specialist**

2012 - 2015

- Early adoption and solution design for ADInstruments' flagship online learning platform
   <u>kuraCloud.com</u> on AWS. This was a migration for hundreds of thousands of clients from Virtual Linux
   Private Servers (VPS) on other providers. Consulting and fault resolution with Amazon directly, as we were hitting the limits of queuing and email sending very early on.
- Working directly with the CTO to define our cloud architectural strategy for future growth and scalability to accommodate one million concurrent users. Including CI/CD pipelines, blue-green and canary (staged) deployments.
- Provided on site training for a major B2B kuraCloud client in Colorado USA, for six weeks on client sites around the USA, including training with AWS.
- Trained Otago University and Polytechnic lecturers and students on the proper use of ADInstruments hardware including mannequins to ensure correct use.
- Tier 2 / 3 support for ADInstruments/kuraCloud's education life science software/hardware products to support Tier 1 support staff globally.
- BAU Systems Administration and 3rd tier support/incident resolution of Cloud technologies and networks for global staff and customers including Salesoforce, Clustered Linux virtual servers (LXC) VMWare, Nagios automated SMS monitoring, OwnCloud, on-premise data centres, Cisco Switches, security and PABX systems, Salesforce and the Atlassian product suite.

# **Highlights**

- Awarded Contributor for the development and implementation of ABIS (Automated Biometric
- Identification System) with the New Zealand Police.
- Managed the global integration of the 104 million dollar JBMS (Joint Management System) project.
- Colorado (USA) life science education products trainer for ADInstruments.
- IT Professionals New Zealand Presenter.
- Audacious Business Challenge Top 40 Finalist.

# **Education / Training**

Otago Polytechnic Bachelor of Information Technology 2010 - 2012

Cisco CCNA 1
Cisco CCNA 2
Cisco PC Essentials
ITIL V3
RedHat Certified Systems Administrator (RHCSA)
RedHat Certified Engineer (RHCE)

## **Referees**

Available on request.